<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Feedback on Professor</title>
    <link>//localhost:4321/categories/feedback/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Feedback on Professor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:4321/categories/feedback/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What Is Good Feedback?</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/blog/color-themes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/blog/color-themes/</guid>
      <description>Everyone reading this has both received and sent out a lot of feedback. Despite this, being able to formulate what is good feedback is still difficult. Is good feedback outcome-oriented, effort-based, unconditionally positive; should its purpose be to motivate, to increase academic outcome, to bring comfort? The difficult part of intuitively getting a definition is that everything seems correct. Feedback should both focus on outcome and effort, it should be positive yet constructive, it should bring comfort while motivating, and ultimately it should ensure positive academic outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Administer Good Feedback</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/talk/second-seedling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/talk/second-seedling/</guid>
      <description>The discussion of application will be rooted in the discussion outlined under the Theory section, and specifically call back to the 7 aspects highlighted there.&#xA;The application techniques will be explained in detail so that you can use them directly, then at the end will be a more theoretical explanation.&#xA;Give clear guidelines for assignments During any assignment, whether a presentation, project, essay, or exam, be open and honest to your student about your grading criteria.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
