<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Attention on Professor</title>
    <link>//localhost:4321/categories/attention/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Attention on Professor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:4321/categories/attention/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What Is Attention?</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/blog/social/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/blog/social/</guid>
      <description>Attention is such a fundamental concept that discussing what it means seems pointless. However, any fundamental concept always carries with it misconceptions perpetuated through tradition. It seems most fitting to start with these misconceptions and then move on to the implications of their dispelling.&#xA;1. Attention is not continuous. An experiment done by Bunce et al. (2010) in the chemistry department at the Catholic University of America was designed to answer three questions regarding student attention:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Gain and Maintain Attention</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/talk/campfire/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/talk/campfire/</guid>
      <description>Based on the Theory, there are four things to center our applications around:&#xA;Allow for Internal/External shifts Novelty Intensity Movement/Motion The application techniques will be explained in detail so that you can use them directly, followed by a more theoretical explanation at the end.&#xA;Chunk your material No matter the lecture length split the material into ~10-minute chunks. These chunks should ideally contain a slight separation of material, e.g., if you are covering Maslow&amp;rsquo;s hierarchy of needs impact on motivation, have one chunk be the details of Maslow&amp;rsquo;s ideas and one chunk be how it pertains to motivation.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
