<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Emotional Bond on Professor</title>
    <link>//localhost:4321/categories/emotional-bond/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Emotional Bond on Professor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:4321/categories/emotional-bond/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to build a student-teacher bond</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/blog/seedling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/blog/seedling/</guid>
      <description>Many of us have a teacher or professor whom we remember fondly. That educator did something that made us feel connected to them, and subsequently more engaged and interested in the material, as well as feeling better. This is the impact of a student-teacher emotional bond. Yet, many of us do not fully understand the impact these bonds have, what they actually do, and then how to build them. This section will cover the benefits and mechanisms of a quality student-teacher bond, and the Application section will delve into how to build it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Create an Emotional Bond</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/talk/bond/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/talk/bond/</guid>
<<<<<<< HEAD
      <description>Given the discussion in the Theory section, we need to consider the five aspects of student-teacher bonds, those being:&#xA;1. Trust in benevolence&#xD;2. Trust in honesty&#xD;3. Affective commitmnet&#xD;4. Affective conflict 5. Satisfcation&#xD;Out applications to build an emotional bond should then target these five aspects. The application techniques will first be explained in detail so that you can use them directly, then at the end will be a more theoretical explanation.</description>
=======
      <description>Given the discussion in the Theory section, we need to consider the five aspects of student-teacher bonds, those being:&#xA;1. Trust in benevolence 2. Trust in honesty 3. Affective commitmnet 4. Affective conflict 5. Satisfcation Out applications to build an emotional bond should then target these five aspects. The application techniques will first be explained in detail so that you can use them directly, then at the end will be a more theoretical explanation.</description>
>>>>>>> 33b35f713d67fd18e719d7884301887a3f0a1894
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
