<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Style on Professor</title>
    <link>//localhost:4321/tags/style/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Style on Professor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:4321/tags/style/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What Drives Student Motivation?</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/blog/fonts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/blog/fonts/</guid>
      <description>Motivation is an innate concept, that is both hard and simple to define. Simply, it is why we do what we do. Yet, what drives motivation, the reason behind the why, is significantly more complex. Despite the singular name for motivation, it is not a singular entity; Motivation is highly varied between individuals. While some might value the praise and pride that comes with academic achievement, others simply do not care about it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Is Good Feedback?</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/blog/color-themes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/blog/color-themes/</guid>
      <description>Everyone reading this has both received and sent out a lot of feedback. Despite this, being able to formulate what is good feedback is still difficult. Is good feedback outcome-oriented, effort-based, unconditionally positive; should its purpose be to motivate, to increase academic outcome, to bring comfort? The difficult part of intuitively getting a definition is that everything seems correct. Feedback should both focus on outcome and effort, it should be positive yet constructive, it should bring comfort while motivating, and ultimately it should ensure positive academic outcomes.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
